The story starts with the principal. I ask, whoami, so the session can establish operating identity.
That makes the relationship explicit: I am the principal, and Codex is the agent acting on my behalf.
Next I ask for my preferences. They add behavioral context for memory, Linked Data, and presentation.
With that context established, I invoke the A2A client skill.
The skill discovers what capabilities an endpoint offers, then supports selection of the skill that matches the task.
The endpoint is chosen by the user. The client reads the endpoint's Agent Card instead of relying on hardcoded assumptions.
The discovery table shows the task URL, authentication mode, streaming support, and published skill count.
The skills-by-endpoint table is the crux: it turns an endpoint into a catalog of callable capabilities.
On URIBurner, the selected skill of interest is OpenLink Data Twingler version 2.0.4.
From there, the workflow can continue into authorization and task execution. OAuth and token capture worked in live QA.
The reusable product pattern is simple: establish identity, establish preferences, invoke A2A, discover skills, and select the skill that matters.